At this point, you've seen a lot of C
syntax and learned the semantics of it,
how to execute it by hand.
So far, the only type you have
seen is int, as in int x = 3.
You're probably wondering about types and
what exactly int means, or for
that matter, what exactly a type is.
In the upcoming lesson, you're going to
learn the answers to these questions and
many other things about types.
All of this is going to build on one
key principle of computer science,
everything is a number.
Computers can only operate on numbers, so
all data has to be
represented numerically.
Types tell the computer how to interpret
and operate on the numeric representation.
As you progress through this lesson,
you will learn about other
built-in types besides int.
You will also learn about implicit type
conversions and explicit type casting.
As well as how to make your
own types to represent
whatever data you need to work with